{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> are integers, the equation 5<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 6<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> = 138 has<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>no solution for <i>x<\/i> < 100 and <i>y<\/i> < 0.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>no solution for <i>x<\/i> > 150 and <i>y<\/i> > \u2013 120.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>a solution for \u201336 < <i>x<\/i> < \u201330.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>a solution for 43 < <i>y<\/i> < 70.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<br ><span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the expressions <i>a<\/i><sub>1<\/sub> \u2013 2<i>a<\/i><sub>2<\/sub>, 2<i>a<\/i><sub>2<\/sub> \u2013 3<i>a<\/i><sub>3<\/sub>, 3<i>a<\/i><sub>3<\/sub> \u2013 4<i>a<\/i><sub>4<\/sub> and 4<i>a<\/i><sub>4<\/sub> \u2013 <i>a<\/i><sub>1<\/sub> are in arithmetic progression, what is the ratio of <i>a<\/i><sub>1<\/sub> and <i>a<\/i><sub>2<\/sub>?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8 : 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Rohan and Sohan together completed a task in a certain number of days. Had each of them worked independently on the task, they would have taken <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">d<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> more days and <\/span><img height=\"32\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAgCAYAAAAffCjxAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAALmSURBVEhL5ZVdSJNRGMcXYriFOg0k8GLemEGFoJuhVqRl2wgEnfdl4WaJ3Ungou9G0y60jxtrgnmheWPTLuY0UsOcSYUTN2ewmYYXGsr8wKnhv3fPe8TN9x2Y3dUfDnuf33nOn\/c8Z+9zJNihtUAAFRUVcI6OMrKtbrsdBoOBRlPTK0Z5CYyuXS2HRCKBwzHECK8n9XWIjo5GYWEhdMXFlFNVdYPNhhg5BgehzMyghOCw27vZDOAcGSGmN5QzAly5XErs85evFJPRr40NgkpVFkwmEz13ddkpIag7t28RW+W2vaXA6iqsVivm5+cpJqP1tTXYbDYCfb3vBUZa9XkkJR1CQ0MD0tPToVAoUFl5HZubLIGToEadHVaB0QmVClKpFHFxcTAajTBWV1NORmYmVlZWKEdg9LazQ2iUlUWsvf0NI0BrSwux1tbXFO\/K6NzZfO7E9iPAlWBLP6anKe\/uvfsU78roppHfisvlZgRwu1zEnj57TnHEGtlsXYwA4243Ma32Ap3Sot8PrUZD7PvUFOXs6o2CarRYsI\/jMTExkMmkiIqKgsXSyGZFjJaWFjE2Nsb9LjOyLZ\/Pi+bmZu7zaILX62WUl8Bor\/qXjdra2lBSUoKioqI9D51OB4nP58Pw8PBfj\/\/11Oq5Pp2dnQ0V14\/M5hosL\/O9R0wRjUovXaRvTqPRQl9WRs85ObkIhLTbUIkafRoaooWhzf5dTw+xFy8tjIRL1OhxbQ0tGhj4yAivg4mJKChQsyhcokbBOyxo1NvXzwh3Qayv44BMhpOnTjMSLlEjj8fD1yQ3F37\/IjHTwwfE1GotxTsVsdi1NWZaGBsbS9dPcnIy5PJ45OXls4xwRTQKKthizWYz6urqsbCwgJQUBc78idHMzAz0egM8E98Y4bY7zvftR9z\/SUyiRnOzs7QoLe0IfJOTcDqdOH7sKOLlcszN\/WRZ4Yq4tQ\/9\/Ticmspd1UlISEiAUqnCRMgbhgv4DeQ2lVya1DQYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"font-family: Arial; vertical-align: middle;\" width=\"18\" \/><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">d<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> more days respectively. If they received a total of Rs.7000 for completing the work, what is Rohan&rsquo;s share?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.3000\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.4200\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.4000\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.3500\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A change dispensing machine contains one-rupee, two-rupee and five-rupee coins. The total number of coins in the machine is 200. The total amount in the machine adds up to Rs.450. If the number of one-rupee and two-rupee coins are interchanged, the total amount comes down to Rs.325. The number of five-rupee coins in the machine is<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>25.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>30.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>15.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Which of the following statements are definitely false?<\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlhVgJcAfcAAP\/\/\/wAAAN3d3YmJiWlpaaenp0dHRyMjI8PDw\/f397+\/v5+fn39\/f0hISEBAQB8fH+fn52hoaAcHBz8\/P19fX7e3t9\/f34aGhi8vLxgYGFdXV5eXlyAgIHh4eM\/Pz+\/v74eHh8fHx2dnZzg4OHBwcFBQUI+Pjzc3N66uroKCgujo6BEREdDQ0NfX16+vr2BgYJ6enlhYWG9vb46OjigoKHd3d09PTw8PDzAwMBYWFj4+PkNDQ5aWlrm5uRoaGkFBQTExMYODgxAQEAgICLOzswYGBnt7e62traGhoV5eXgsLCw4ODh4eHjo6OlJSUp2dnT09PTMzMwkJCaampra2tuDg4Ly8vCYmJjQ0NDU1NQUFBVFRUQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAAVgJcAQAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzhz6tzJs6fPn0CDCh1KtKjRo0iTKl3KtKnTp1CjSp1KtarVq1izat3KtavXr2DDih1LtqzZsyEDCKColuEAAgAKGIh4IACBAB7bKiQwAOOAAIABr00oIDBejAYKFERg2G7KwgjfekwMgHLFAwgUQqbIt7LizhwxR2QMGO5F0AMRHACw2aTqgp1FG5Q7UfbAv4YHA8gtsLDhuQJxB1BcsLVIvRKRJ5RM+6HxjsoPoq4oWWCB1QgZZ44bXaLl1NgFBv\/YDrM6R8rfPz6fSHl6RtsNWxvoa9H96\/UiXx+EP7A5XfLBmRbXaoURpx1rhwl0gGL+jcdSdw61dYABpRVUQGly1aUXhcMVFxhjAnFIAFyyYSbAhGr5liBBdgFmIGDYgfYhAAesdeFaA9BnkHn4hUhccMARRFoAfckV2GB1TfijQPoJ5B4AwmU2omN3EbljleFx2BdkRgp2oWOBLTmQhoqppiGAAFQpV5VBHmmQb\/SZiKIAX2a2GW4CjmljWznypeaUAYRHUJX9AQacARzOxSECBtzVF4dixhVkk6kFViSHG5amI4KBFqZmcBXOBtgAq4HWmYqmfUlAqXeN2JdoUZL\/NhdpMbZKI4wKoskjXtNdhyBBkqFmXm94qYgmAENuChGEDUk4V2G6BcidlHCNKB6akEE2AHCOlYhAgdcOaJBj0EIL5VyxlYlXjmk6aMCx0loX5LgejrsWY3Q6aG1njIlJqYNCYkdqmgIDt2BBf1GbpmnjcakvXMFuuWKIEgvQ77kGoYedgweDWBBlEn7b4W4WE4iXr5Upy+5dmb3bWXuHHRwwlHB5bK0BG2cmGqJOMowtYAq1he+FCktWmLL3WekryvN5uBbOadIXm50NHwb1qk6+ioB+A9Nm7rYEZ62g1ggLSFuNBaW44sEXzlsvZZSKdy+zC9Fd91reli2pvCTH\/ztQtni9K623m\/nHn14EFGCeWnydOFBijFYW23KNETbxbkHTCRxtG\/rbmLKLlRrndv4B2dtqaNPM5eZzSfZXQgnypV\/cntXuWZPpYU6QiYdF\/nfgBgqKrKKTv\/yZ1CpvChpkllG2M3F6Dfu4m7Brzrds9plMrO1xV\/eaqcpi5r3oYsP3Gm2LC\/Dk1AhX3vfuAqgYqni41os1Q3ZXzxbe2\/HHHOu7MUyefgUZ2UiGcIf50oxYNBC+CEcwsgtP4jA3nsQMEFgXRMjE8IMp60mqNROcWZrcxiJcgUZDhtLbr\/RSAAKsjm\/VSVS9gjOA2Qmvds0rwJBcRJDn8I5vv6uMYf9uiJcKtjBqtQMfbJRXuRzSqGXQE6BCXpexIzWHc4Nh18w2w7whIow+jlNiuwCDgOWRD4myCcxq0NcY9elIgWTDoEFSNxC1BeeGIXLbZjSUwQ5OJH\/6y5scrzgXugGuMtuRjOCeWDgSsmgwiZNe47KkmPkUMoQHkV5CLAOX0iEIeh7Eoo9CN6YL3ghZZ+QPsIDjuNS95YV7k57M6tjAGmKHdughDuTwuL3diQyI28vdx8Bml+MlEXlLHJSynPg8uSVkOsoBF8kI+USxbfEwzIvUbUzzGi12xkpPHB8S0YiAU56vdQMEDc\/IqUJlOgmVv8pjrsAzwzoCSJqAPEg+9cn\/v3kOEoDWSlm9tMUtuDRNO61xkLlYVDO1zQ2N6rKOlSgUrXYu5EC4QZN+7hJKdDXUX+E5kBxpdEawLax9a9mXz2CJvmqNbpgIKhmTbpjLUcoMYI9TjGh+KLdDosykBLnQo9pivHFmb28e8xUzodgzii2GhcLbqFqoCbajkZKLJyuY0yqzGpMS6U5Ve9oZp1adA6zxWULj1UsZE8dtvqlDX1JMa8A1sKb2EHjOpGe7KhqhlILubtUMbKUSA0AhOmagVtMUpxD1S2KRcVxV2s6Q\/Eo\/gBVGSoUdqWbTZiiOfmxUC6LmrZREygZeLkyM0xGbrpTCEI3qV9RkzFw09Fcyj8HztsAikhMDOLK7Hpan3OkQWAN1kMuOUGx\/eQsyYSMYiQLNdjCTy49EdJAh4VFLoS2siEAnGGweBjd4lBV2aNuXKhGgaaoaK9lQGz\/iTnacXzoA2PyXwVsFKmHG+QuOAnPBzYSpikSa5VSEGZP6SucpmkSLgkfDywVvpUrgrAkC\/nqQAmgTKQl2sIYVQrsN\/3v4wyAOsYhHTOISm\/jEKE6xilfMYgV\/j8IakeXWePkkhnS4xTjOsY5LO5IE37jGF23wjodMZLPg5mmJ7MuR4Xmq136WSHGE1QLNS6K7XGfGrgUabpQcqgNYGVW4LbKYxyyWFx6RRu1FKvlAFq2qWslbXDureKqcq26aplFIZNqrTCOay96YzIAONFXOPCbWzIXQTO7L5fzJPsHC0zIH7B+W5VhUeKoSM38WtKY3rRRJTljJeXpxj1wZ5e2oMbBHhPMt+YtETBHXNhCeNKdnTWsMD3DCBsBRqEU36u28TNLmXA2kSSTp7wnMpbYbk6lHl+laO\/vZN4FMk8y6vde8uHp28HHzo\/qinbKucWPErrOw5UqlImm1z98dT7Ohze52uySjtbzNY6\/tmwuySWIBYCxvT0nlwGJ6NUNammPAy+jSzMfaQna3wheukn02BMgMj7jEv8IYA08E4hPPuMY3zvGOe\/zjIA+5yEdO8pKb\/OQoT7nKV87ylrv85W4wj7nMZ07zmtv85jjPuc53zvOe+\/znQA+60IdO9KIb\/ehIT7rSl870pjv96VCPutSnTvWq53Z+Vs\/6wu9XGUdq\/euz9uGFwU52QCOaZmVP+6ald3a1u53IZ8\/w2+fOYi4+aux0zzuKsSYACiVc7\/+AJ7EC2xb4whv+8IhPvOIXz\/jGO\/7xkI980hOggAUwoAEOcMADDPOAzDeAAQtQQAIkT\/qmQKAAEXiABCZAAQZUQAEKsABBLAD7CjCAAhOQwAMiUAAIlP73K2mMxQ9igQtgIAMa2IDsJ2KBDWggAxi4wPKX5UXgWx+wCsL7QBKwgAZwoAMe4IgHOsCBBixg9H19HIyvb33kYBwAH2BABihQAZFUgAIZYMAHmqUbT7L\/\/8ihSgMRfw+gfyZBgAaYOer3fwxYR4YBYyBQgPuXEgQIAkHzGw2YgfkTAhjQARPIEh\/QARgQAhq0JxmogXy1fSIwAuEXEx4wAiKAfo\/kJH9Ld4KPxywQMAEbYBMbMAG+N4PisX42eIMpyIEkeBNGCITTMoQ2WAAO8IM4AQEOoH1MmIEkoAEymBMJoAEkUIVeCH8lYAJAYQIl8IFf\/9iAFnACKCAUKXAC03eG7KcCK8ACQmECJNACGGCGcAh8DjAAJZCFPOECJSAQCuAAe3h9JCCGFfCHPhECDiCDdniIv7cAFDAQiwiIN9ECI6CHFLAAkih5jpiFFbCJOgEBI\/CGApEADnCEn9h4EIABUDgQHuAAejgTCcCCCPGKsdiKiJcAE8CKBTGLtRgTDVB\/CRECE4CJvBh4LwADCiGMNREBO7gQMPACy4h4CjABDAGNMgECHeAQE6AA11h4CYABLdAQ3PgSBRADD+EBJ6CM46h23tiOtPgSlwgRHWCB8Uh3EPAA8IgQ6agSAdkQCfAAu7iPZScDMyARL4iKJmEBDnHgkA0xAzKAkG7Xj\/+oEC0QkRToAC0oEQV5kBaZdQpZERApkSCRACVgjBRBkSNJdhhpESdpEi\/giRYRki\/5dRfwjRcxkyPBAAyQER1wATmpdRjwkTLJkSGxANaYER6AAUVpdS1AAxvhkx5RAQ3AETRwjv9ROXU1QJRVqZTiNwIZKREXUANdOXUPgJImiYtVOQIiKZMPkJZRZwEc8BFSiJQW8QEjwJUdwQFsSZdGF4kf8QEeiREJ0ADi+BGJKJhOZwMuEBKGqZcSEQNUWBEuYAOO2XQ3MIwbMZkV0ZiSeQObuXRPSRKgKRGEKRJHWZpJVwAaUBKp+RCCWBIacJmuuXNAeYCH6RChWBK7mZtGZ5knYZgsqRAWgAOe6RHrKJxG15rFuZIL8QE4EJgdcZrOSXSdmRIqeZwFoYrAiJqkmZ1Dt2gk0Z0IUYwNR57lyRLoWRDSGHzsGXR22RLvKRDzuBKAOZ8\/V5\/2KZ1xwY4ssZ\/82XMx\/mmfOQAYOlCWIkGgBbpzB8oSCrQDLuGgD5pzEboSCuR1JmGhF3pzCSABMMEhKXgS5sj5oTR3olmhoigacxLAoFQRoi2qc9DZEqfGEtg5ozdHnC1hQBw6Es2pozdXA\/q4EsbhcBwBAmgppDYHmy5RF\/CCErfJpDYXAiPwEsKBmx5Ro1Q6c9sJEyKFEh8wnl1Kc5ApofNCYCORmWVac6vZcMSxUCghmm0qczkafNSTElxapzCXAXFJFRCQAXxKcyW5FS45qDJnpVwxAuGJqC63llphAXPpqDIXnFhhqZT6cjF5FTiZqTFXqFZxqJ4Kc1OJFVs5qjJ3plXBptaoGnMvCKNHcYuU2aosB6pRIaq0+nKdChWbmqswx6pQoaq+GnMlsIZPgQKDOKwy9wEYYJ1DYQF5qKwz1wInsJxD8QEn4JfSGnMV8KNCYQDeua0w96ZGQafiOnPNiBTVeK4254uNChTICKvsinIQ4IZEkYZ\/Oq8u95TvuhMc6Kz6ynIfMAHO+BMwMAHWGrC6+gJd2BMk8ALyqrAsZwIGkLAv8QEGIIYSy3MVYK83kYbhurE4h4cha4\/mKLI\/9wENYAP5ihIQYAMNYLEoW3MuQANg6RIXQAORqDmzQvcBNcABNqkSC8ABNSCzPItzFvACQIsSQ\/sCAHu0EKq0HfC0FGEB5Oe0ULt0xfcAI7ABRusQH7ABI\/AA0pe1TxcCEXADHViyDlEBIngDEdCvZst0HgACDRAAE6ABDOACcgsACuACDKABExAADQACszq3U6cABcAANjACjdEYDmADDFAAi4m4lnu5mJu5mru5nNu5nvu5oBu6oju6pFu6pnu6qJu6qv+7uqzbuq77urAbu7I7u7Rbu7Z7u7i7Y6LxfnMUpUHUIwihKkIYEcCrbBfxQMjBGxYRNxD2WAoSGByBpAohgG4xfAdBIdaLENTbSxLhSQQmvfEmEtu7HMPXI\/43Sh1RvA8xvnpzvhPhvgyxu8NbEOx7SA\/BuxOhvo42EebhK9IUphPBvG+EHZaBMhkBvtrru1OUvWlTohmhv8HrrXXkwAuBvxbBvplUvix6vVrqHBvcEBjsVvAbESM8vVIyv75EI9RVQmrRIiPzJW5DZdxWGmphQwtDJU72O5EFKr9FNYLhOGGDSBkcRL1yQxqyMVriXFxnTc4UgGgCYU\/jKIYlJhr\/QhngEjlD8lbg5GWhoiK6lm9jZC0ENy6PtUA8jFOONTonQlF1Ek948jGZcSAtlCHNBTc8tBtVQmFoc0p9giUOKDRm5by781gBxReLYl9UAylOUhp3dsekcRcRPEImxEN5PGfjsVqVBUnPBb1CUj+G5V1bbF47kkKqQseZIlxzMihHIiu1ccL\/ocIxdVcIYm7IchgBFW\/flBn6ZcP3Y1ICZlUgomfV5CBKpTOHYZ79O1sVpRwnpGgNFU9Q407WQcC9ZSHAcV5dZ1doTDKRI1RQMgBf4zZsBsvmQsxdlUAFtRnu0THHHC1x9jGKETL4JFNcQsCbckR\/8RkW9jDY1liO\/+ExO1Je7lJGMaNTEXUxQOVU5vIuvrMzFWNVS1NQJ7UbmUFU5kkbkEwjlaQYvhzP3EbABl3L8GQ0G8Qn6BQiBhXPeINW0SLMzMHPAVU1YtIc2FzCCSG\/ryxI24NV4\/QcnSE7bSJTieZPpSMfjBI8T+Q74fQqDF1fyJtXeoIQ3zQYaiFOqqy8wRVhs6EooOQ3TUwzikInAqIcEwNnQSI+d0YckqHVf0NJ72MQcVPWjaXUv2IZlBJG1iJne5MYQDzBUC0kxPMqRmVLOWXDQWRNZoUkjRU1PD1s7\/MWzWG+6IJMzkM6hbQW0oRbiaFF3Os3yrHW9Ctpg4LU\/8M30eNCKv9KGzadwOO0vjoj2r\/rXWPEybg8AA0i1NdmX611OjnlaqhTTkHC0O8yH5AdGRdER3+d1YpG1W7E29Jczb8jJirC1ZWFdX0z3PjSVQJCRz4EbME9YXxGOg0lyLg1Qd1xo53NSOgsy75NvyeiGt0MQLvUwMlNS0aEbFGzQ8Nh2I5lKXal3g\/I07JxRMK3OJGsRM6DgSy0yo3RQpvyHMg7N6XR3f6Evo5T2nsjfPgx3XvTyq3tEDsF2zst2xD30zUU1ECc29Rr1LmDaWdd0TnCKMi9WdZUM8KzTlMtN1YdvgdCKdNBRbRhGXTDJ6\/TKJ001rpB4Un94jGk1nliwKzh1sr\/EWyy7EuNxN5jxxeo0xnUNN9AyCyWhMfGlN9RdUuCsh6MQgCS9hyN7eRv3eGSPdj9TN+rJMBV7laDcmxKDh8hZGcdLkqHnVt8s9r74coQEeIVTkCynVTCY+IUDSUOFTagYVK3PMvcIS4YIxrmvMgV3WCaBC5xFdq1vNw91RbRHL5BLF\/29NzUPdFNM4OF0TrCZdLwXE15s+nVgTJ2ceW7E1Fv7m21HuIJlWb1bDqdXC3ELN86VdFroRfM4s0UJec3NWlx8+oHgzbj1TJxUgA8revVcmeKJiUXPdliQxmUDheAPDjQg2VeU9IPZcWOUdn+BiAu3UkABe7rISOHJsGsxs0vNWjrIv68HlM4tF3btdwiPDwwqIHJOtxckE5c1eTFEjU2TOzVg3xfaBxfxMTcwbXEH\/5bZtzfF5JsK0wQFKIzRZIgWewhPTxPEm8e\/aZA+uS80cFevhXerRHqw4VHHVJXXa4u4OTsaeYhmFXj9PFf\/D0mr\/XqGN0htBVP6szIWcZNNBxme6NEyTVG3JJFnvxfY4QkyvFeAWcyLb+\/uAEcsiVa1LUeKjLyhfHvRrFuKiEAKOx2DKwUd69z8nMTNbR4\/K4U6v+Tu4I\/+DvXvA5\/wQDiHnLHEGp60+6j3\/HcGH8\/xE9WzSi0yG00GXinLXnPuo0vEXxe9w3x+YXeQDb+O4MBwQshS2NNHwUsKKRfEosvu58\/eOdC24ZiG1v2FvlG0hUS63csIinNKaC8zbaBcCkcT2QMxsA\/Mv3WH\/NSzrphGwSGKSg9UXdcKM\/F1y58IsTF+ZX1LKn8uo1P8JD+NHe3hPFGRZGGICJDy141\/JsON8IDa6fPvRwEPdyuNHp9WAABAACBAgINGihoIEBBgwcZNhxAQKABiQYMCCQgEUAABA0DCAAQEQBCAQEGDPwI4ACCkiErMlxY8mFDmjVt3sSZU+f\/Tp49ff4EGlToUKJFjR5FmlSpTYQ8W4p02VLgyoYETkKFanCl1JYGOrocWaDAxakICBy4eSDA2gBoASBgu\/YrAKk4SQYQ2JVh1rA0CQoswPakw5wim24ECVarxokFpI5t\/JRxZLxLLV\/GnFnzZs6dPX8Wehin2rWKIyJwO3LuwKsaoRJgy7JyS6pgEQaO25H0ZJUd4SZGfbMuzQFsHc\/GW7vA5L8NReddSLgm3LUvBcYNMLnk2oTHAZO9a9r4cNDlzZ9Hn179etDPacLtKFlgxLq1MbaeL9FkWa54veYPC7KbOGqotuIECs4m8qbSKDy6\/NtrMgEL6OijBO+Triq3\/wyDKTGc4ArrMfC8E+mABr1jL0UVV2SxRRczc68hARUyraKTAlvNqhqlKk426EIiK7u+CCxJgMNS0mouE99KjaYFEQMgMBRbKsAtIQuUaDuNDhhso7libKok6wZqsEsog3NwRhL1A0nKJ1+EM04556TTM9F0LJA7jrDSaC0D7IsyOz5Rys6AAfqbqLqTwoztOu5osg8uCpts6MniAqCIAEQJzagm2PQcjDQCMzSIuoXQEk2hK0tlC6Q0R5Tv0kzrW61OW2\/FNVddKzWTxRh3BTZYYYclttgVB6h1vU\/3M7ZZZ5+FNlppp6W2WmuvxTZbbbfltltvvwU3XHHHJbdccxrPRTdddddlt11334U3Xnnnpbdee+\/FN1999\/\/lt19\/\/wU4YIEHJrhggw9GOGGFF2a4YYcfhjhiiSemuGKLL8Y4Y4035rhjjz8GOWSRRya5ZJNPRjlllTH+QAGXQWAgZgZccNmDlW\/G2dgQQIjBgQBumCDoDmRmwIagMQiABgcYKACCnJ+G+sUWTLBBghE6KEABn1pQgAENMsCABBcSiLpss3vCjjeeINgAAxrEJtsoD6jO4AWtz8Y77+s8PGAmnRSwIYMIbL7sgwUmeICBD\/RmHGokWePJhREmcMEzCxh4oAanG+c85ccBtckFDGwIwbwPLnhAhsU7Z31k7HqlCYIGbCAcvQRmoGGB1nf\/+PGcQHigAhUhoMCBFnj\/Rz5j321qAYMO4l5RAQxASL56ipenqYATam8xgQ4aWN168RnGXqAERNAgfDgroKF0nS5ddXz5\/f3gBB5shWAEGHI66yCy5gdgviyAAe7V6QXUU1BltOK3ADYQXh44gQV21QES2GQ5xFGbAzWorh744AcM2IAC1FcnE7ygJnyJUgY3uEJyeQAIHAgCAyLgACEMwQExmNnd5ASCDmSPNyhkYRDDZQEHWEB2DdhcAhRQAAaUwGcZcEAEGKCAAqaIBCao1GwWxUAhdnFb9TueQNinO5tAQAEbYIADcJA0B3TABAqQ4Ho0MJP+GaktXsSjt0bgPoN84AUNiKNOuAYCEjiA\/wMBGEEDGLAABUDPMwkwgA4Dpaf\/5dGS1YrZTdiHQKCEoAIMeIEDhmDDF8yMj5mBAAY2d0lWbksBE8iJ90YQRqIocQFNHEEAoEiCKdIyKQpwQCuFia1UrhInIcABAxx5FDOaII00YCMD3mhMoWRymNeUVgOEx5MEMAAHp7wM1xhQyAwgsgRMayRQ9ohNdjarABoASguutszNhMAFDOjZEITggFJWAJw18QAG2jlQYX2ABtTsCQhosM3ztOyWDcglBxxAAhAowJcAuCJBNZorEWyAKBZowAtGmB4LKMAEHXAANHGwtA0Q4QAI3WhMWxTQoyxgoXDyQNdmWIQA3BCdMh0FqopsUDlmNgCJcfpACYzwgCMwsWcB2KcUK1DFoP9WFTM0VcoYX+SBEVRuBjKgScvQ2IA1SrQDFQ2kVdVqlAh4dCl+BCSLCjBL8z0Apg0pKQ8NGQAcKDKEI11rYG8CgQfQEymbVBEJYuDIrwbFA5+cYQ19SjPBVrYh1sSMLC9ang84AIuxK6xRlMhEJ+oyilOkqmU1+oC0YgaZzzuPB3AgyYYM9TJmRKMa2ehGOKp2oCEYwSNB8M3yzLW1DXGBDTwzyEIeMpGLTKdvL9lW0MgTtp1RrGEbkoG7csaToBQlKU0pXSHeALCbAQEHGIqZzn5WJxlNkS1xaVpeWpS8AMSqeWQn0qvOtifJjVMznxnNaZpHVXG5L8Qwex6bElX\/Kcb1SQJuoF2pdY2c5kQnhZcCugQzzAG01W8JjnqUBERgsUCZAIhxZU98inKf\/fwnUjjc4YRJWMOf0WpRIOAAtwJlwcRyKAMgGgCJUtS+RpkxjQ8G3BXBdbM9QWaMeVKBBlSrpCdNKV9ZqoDupiVZSj7YAijQogrggJM+2YADuqwTCzyAWzmVoQPK6dOs6STJYCZYDc6sIs32pMQRuPFOJBBoay2xxVA9bQU+sMo741lgtn3Ra2+84x4XhYDo+gASkoADJSyhx412NMAuDacEDFfKAIhyUiA9LgWAoARCoMELFnBRUIfaX4Oek3VHmuY1\/+Ss4PqAC1Da0w644Ly2L16YAuekUIb+mdA++fG1WrCAF9BACCWoKLItlgAJ3Gq\/i+bxZUBQA2ztrAQZiPWs\/7WdMQtwIFcLYIIPTl0Uak\/rAxUY9tVc0Ot1Q6zduTJBE5ww4qXU21nTjoC1G5Dtfn\/s37ZKQAwqCIAcK8XgwzI3ul+wgSc3nGMPp5MFRjATPxrP4ibc1b3zXWx+e5zd7qaTAnBAVZnvmSgXrxPCFc5wl3uOTiZwwLH7bJRouyjjseZ4z3OmbBdFfOI6CQENrjuUorNH5T7Td8uVPjLzwknkXMSJqYkC3xRZYAERwIEQFq7ireds1C2SeWpzomuhrBo9ITDBuTmwcbm3\/WkxALt6QBB0ojA7KDTouGbunUZEik3rfr9Z1dGT1B4a5ds\/YbpmzI52tU8R8rx754rk6cfgmtIg8DRpAQ3qmfcM7H0Dff884\/K7HsklfigQiAHBcQLgt34S646Pvfy6vp4mHtsoFb8J2Yuy+bQrku3Br57dTXdOzviRrjd5e1Dwrne+Q3+DJni6eUb\/GWTaHAAfuAFQEuD7IYwA+N5n4exBU\/vyyLKAvGdzAdA+BOc\/G\/7y4y7zKL67w4Gpo66bwLsYaL0YeL3\/Y6UauADQSCoGYA+xS4AMUJ\/1S6P2I4GmccBhkj\/N4CrSUw95IoEniAEAsAD9wwH+myL\/\/\/vAIMq+zJgr2zsPEpAAKFjABoxBjbqAytOM7Iov9osCKfDAHpQpwoLBn2iv9VjB\/es\/5UPCmJKBGeiv59uMuYkBDuAABuQeJcQOSpnCa1JCy4Cwz1CiDcSBDjwugbgAcnscQxnDgarCpRBCzlhBEmjBpYkunEgAu4KS75jDdirDo2hCETSBLexCE4A9mnjDvTkI2BnEVuKho5AtLByKNBSlNSyANtyJQsSOSprEYUoADLBBnThDpMjDPXxBo1i1lAiMURyoV8pEE1tCm9BCLowBRsyqKjMIJOkfWWSnGJiCoKC0WuqaTWTDyyhFX3ocZhHGYfoADPBEBCQuoICAArIggRGwoVbUDAogo1\/0EByJxmsKAQd4Nl7zCQ\/YgC3MgF2ct6WAAZQrx6oCv51wNp1IwwYYAhyIgE4UPwy4xXpkpRJAgZw4xsHSRm5cmgoYSKQAI4JUqwQoASqwxn9iR3eEx\/iKJIlcqw+YgCpSRwDYx378x2pEDwNYL4+sKgiIIIP4sypYyG50SDh5gf1hycAaIJuxgivAAg54RxOIR\/ZIgJvMycr6gCzQgiHYAoCsE4rE\/8mjFKykiso66ayVlEqZYgu3KEpAq5OoG8qsxCYD+R8euL44uYAReDyxZKXheBwIqkoWkR1yY0urUosvO78\/OsXywB2srEuZgh8uqgAMuICHXIoQwADV+cvKgg+bSIAayB31sAAKGIFGXEx2EpDGwAkLeAEOWADDFAoP0IAHCMfLtKroeBAPuQnOfIALQMmkSC4MOD3TjKm4UE2ErIEHmIAFML6h8IAIyADpo811U4AXABoQCEuEFDMOwIANWMvhVDIFqIERkIAJACER2gkWowAaqJsFeE3o9Lg0nKEbCIDqDJrznABoQiQbWKS9BM\/PUyKXkc8je8\/6tM\/7xM\/81AjP\/eTP\/vTP\/xoE0AAV0AEl0AI10ANF0ARV0AVl0AZ10FsJCAA7\" style=\"width: 598px; height: 348px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Only I\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Only II\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Both I and II\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Neither I nor II\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">The average age of a family of seven members, including Bunti and Babli, aged 70 years and 63 years respectively, on January 1<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">s<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">t<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> 1986 was 33 years. N years later, Bunti died on his birthday and Mona was born on the same day. A few years after that, Babli died on her birthday and Rohan was born on the same day. N more years after that, on January 1<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">s<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">t<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> 2007, Raj was born. What was the average age of the family of eight members on January 1<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">s<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">t<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> 2008?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>28 years\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>32 years\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>33 years\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>29 years\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There is a 5 \u00d7 5 square grid, with each of its cells having a distinct identity. In how many ways can three identical coins be placed in the grid (with at most one coin in each cell) such that no two coins are placed either in the same row or in the same column?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"600","CORRECT_ANSWER":"600","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">What is the remainder when 5<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">5<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">0<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> is divided by 13?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>12\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Bhagat and Chandu start simultaneously from village X to village Y, with their respective speeds in the ratio of 3 : 2. After travelling one-fourth of the total distance, Chandu triples his speed and travels for some more time, following which, he again changes his speed and completes the rest of the journey. Bhagat, however maintains his initial speed throughout the journey. If both Bhagat and Chandu reach the village Y at the same time, and the time for which Chandu travelled at thrice his initial speed was one-third of his total time of travel, then find the ratio of the respective speeds with which Bhagat and Chandu reach the village Y.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>24 : 7\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>18 : 7\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7 : 2\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 : 2\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The shortest median of a right-angled triangle is 25 units. If the area of the triangle is 336 sq.units, and the length (in units) of the longest median of the triangle is  <img Width='26' Height= '18' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABoAAAASCAYAAABFGc6jAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAKdSURBVEhLpZVfSJpRGMbF6wjbugzULbZBbLta7cIuEtSaDC3Bu\/6stRrGiOxGlP3R25XkxbbW2ty6qPtYW95JSaWwXLACIagWwjSXXUhYZs++835Hp7Rs1Q8OfM\/jOec5fu8555PgFFKpFOx2O3p6es7crFYr0uk0zXNqkM\/ng9FoRCgUOnMLh8N8lv8I6uvrg8fj4er8nBqk1WoRDAa5Oj8lg6LRKFQqFfb397lzfkoGTU1NwWw2c3UxSgY5HA44nU6uLkbJIL1eD7\/fz9VxDg8P+ZPI0dERtX9xYtDu7i7Vh52jHAvz82hpacHY2HtoNBooFAoYDAasr6\/D2t+PmpoaKJVKDA65kc1m+SiRE4NmZ2fpHxXy\/NlTSCQSXK6sxMTkJDzDw6RlMhlaW9sQCARwt66WvGQyyUeJ5IP29vb4k4jL5YLNZuNK5L7+Hk0SDIZIr678IK3VNZJmPOp6SN7vnR3uiEg2NjbQ29uLqqoqOs05mpubMTMzwxVoi1+qqMCd2jruAB+9H2jS6S9fSbP63Lh+DQrlFWQyGfJySLxeLwYGBmiAWq0m8+DgAPX19YjFYqQZqysr1OeF08Ud4HF3N3m\/eL\/E9jbp9o4HpAvJvzp2CbJOy8vLWFtbo2IXMjkxQb9\/np7mDnD71k1h9cp84QNzc9Tn1es3pAvJB21tbUEqlcJkMmFkZIRu3kKeCK+XTbK5+ZP0jlADptvaO0gzhgZfkrewuMgdIBKJ4NP4ePGus1gs1FEulxfVh6FuaMDV6mrh3Ytn53t4CWVlZRgdfUea0dXZifLycmERf3fcW2HRbM6iIHa3kSm0eDzOXZG4UAd2tnKwzcFqmPveMBKJxLFx7FA36nTFQQy2OdxuN1cXZ2npG5oam\/AHx3xDZl09\/2EAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>   find <i>m<\/i>.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"2353","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2353","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Indian Airlines has a certain free luggage allowance for each passenger. It charges for excess luggage at a fixed rate per kg. Two passengers, Mohan and Sohan, have a total of 50 kg of luggage between them. They were charged Rs.2800 and Rs.1400 respectively for excess luggage. If the free luggage allowance were halved and the entire luggage belonged to one of them, the excess luggage charge would have been Rs.6300. Find the weight (in kg) of Mohan\u2019s luggage.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>40\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>25\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>30\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>35\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Let N = 2<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">3<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">3<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> &times; 3<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">1<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">. How many positive divisors of N<\/span><sup style=\"font-family: Arial;\">2<\/sup><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> are less than N but do not divide N?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"693","CORRECT_ANSWER":"693","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">X is a set of the first eight consecutive natural numbers. Find the number of ways in which a subset, Y, of X can be formed such that the sum of the elements of Y is divisible by 3?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"87","CORRECT_ANSWER":"87","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A, B, C and D are four integers having a sum of 4. If the minimum possible value of the sum of their reciprocals is R, find the value of the product 210 &times; R.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"-600","CORRECT_ANSWER":"-600","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">c<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> are in arithmetic progression, then the equation <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a<\/i><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b<\/i><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">c<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> = 0<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>represents a family of straight lines, each of which is at a distance of 5 units from the origin. \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>represents a family of straight lines, all of which intersect at a point P, which is at a distance of 5 units from the origin.\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>represents a family of straight lines, each of which is at a distance of  <img Width='19' Height= '18' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAASCAYAAAC5DOVpAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIiSURBVDhPlZO9a5pRFMatNEI6pYJg+vEHtIXazcUPUBAsGEknFRdxcNPGNi5mkzRO2tUpxc9FmzhUi4goiUKzpougsYLi5BcoOChP3\/d4a0hbX9sHLtznnPv+OPec+4qwQf1+HwcHB3C5XBvXRlgymYTdbketVtu4NsIcDgdSqRRzwhKELRYL6HQ61Ot1FhGWIKzRaECv1xP0XyQIS6fTsFqtzAGVSgWJRAKxWGy1vuRyLLsBxk8xFArRfj6f49HuLkQi0Z317PkLyvMShJlMJlSrVdq3bm4gFotxeOhDt9tFp9NBu91Gr9ejPK+1sPF4DI1Gg8FgQD6fz1ElFxeX5P+mtbBisQiz2cwcEOaue4+rTK1WQyqVQi6Xw\/vuPXf92+GshQUCAfj9fuYA894eVWY0vkY0GoXb7Sa\/v\/9mNW2ClctlqoLvxS\/ZbDZkMhnmgK\/5PE5Ogswt9dazBH67uiIvikQiUCgUFPR4PBSczWbQarXUZCFlz8\/ou3D4I3kR\/zAnkwk1WyKRYDgcotlswmAw0AFePNzn8+H4+AOLLPXp9JRg59ks+VXPSqUSJYLBIHLcQ3Q6nSzD\/VbcG3v65DHlW60fFJtOp3ileImdnYcYjUYUuzMApVIJmUzGNdmIeDzOoktVq5d4sL2N+1tbVDU\/TR6e+XzGTvwGKxQKdGBZQYtFb8W35OjID4vFAq\/Xi+vr7yyz1B9PQ6VS0UD+X8BPl\/R02Ef4QaYAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>   units from the origin. \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>represents a family of straight lines, all of which intersect at a point P, which is at a distance of  <img Width='19' Height= '18' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAASCAYAAAC5DOVpAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIiSURBVDhPlZO9a5pRFMatNEI6pYJg+vEHtIXazcUPUBAsGEknFRdxcNPGNi5mkzRO2tUpxc9FmzhUi4goiUKzpougsYLi5BcoOChP3\/d4a0hbX9sHLtznnPv+OPec+4qwQf1+HwcHB3C5XBvXRlgymYTdbketVtu4NsIcDgdSqRRzwhKELRYL6HQ61Ot1FhGWIKzRaECv1xP0XyQIS6fTsFqtzAGVSgWJRAKxWGy1vuRyLLsBxk8xFArRfj6f49HuLkQi0Z317PkLyvMShJlMJlSrVdq3bm4gFotxeOhDt9tFp9NBu91Gr9ejPK+1sPF4DI1Gg8FgQD6fz1ElFxeX5P+mtbBisQiz2cwcEOaue4+rTK1WQyqVQi6Xw\/vuPXf92+GshQUCAfj9fuYA894eVWY0vkY0GoXb7Sa\/v\/9mNW2ClctlqoLvxS\/ZbDZkMhnmgK\/5PE5Ogswt9dazBH67uiIvikQiUCgUFPR4PBSczWbQarXUZCFlz8\/ou3D4I3kR\/zAnkwk1WyKRYDgcotlswmAw0AFePNzn8+H4+AOLLPXp9JRg59ks+VXPSqUSJYLBIHLcQ3Q6nSzD\/VbcG3v65DHlW60fFJtOp3ileImdnYcYjUYUuzMApVIJmUzGNdmIeDzOoktVq5d4sL2N+1tbVDU\/TR6e+XzGTvwGKxQKdGBZQYtFb8W35OjID4vFAq\/Xi+vr7yyz1B9PQ6VS0UD+X8BPl\/R02Ef4QaYAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>   units from the origin. \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Some chocolates were distributed equally among a few children and three chocolates were left. Had there been four times the number of children, then ten chocolates would have been left. Find the number of children.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>14\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Four-fifths of a number exceeds the square of the number by as much as that by which the cube of the number exceeds four-fifteenths of the square of the number. How many such numbers lie in the interval [&ndash;1, 1]?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">If <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">g<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">) = <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">g<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">) + <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">g<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">) &ndash; 2, <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">g<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(2) = <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">a<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">g<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(3) = <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">b<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, then the value of <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">g<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">(72) =<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3<i>a<\/i> + 2<i>b<\/i> \u2013 8\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2<i>a<\/i> + 2<i>b<\/i> \u2013 6\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3<i>a<\/i> + 3<i>b<\/i> \u2013 8\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2<i>a<\/i> + 3<i>b<\/i> \u2013 8\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If the<b> <\/b>sum of 101 distinct terms in arithmetic progression is zero, in how many ways can three of these terms be selected such that their sum is zero?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"1250","CORRECT_ANSWER":"1250","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A hexagon is inscribed in a circle of radius 14 cm. If three of the sides of the hexagon are 22 cm each and the other three sides are all equal, find the length of each of the other three sides.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7 cm\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Find the maximum possible value of the product <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">, where <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> is given by the solution to the equation | <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 3 | = 4 and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> is given by <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">y<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> = 7 &ndash; | <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">x<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> &ndash; 2 |.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>49\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>14\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A group of boys met in a playground and pooled some marbles in a bag, such that each boy contributed exactly two marbles more than the number of boys in the group. One of the boys responsible for the safe keeping of the marbles then took the bag home. After reaching home, he opened the bag to count the number of marbles and found that there were exactly 288 marbles and also realized that the bag had a hole in it. Just as he was wondering if any marbles had fallen out of the hole on his way home, his friend arrives and confirms that he had found a couple of marbles that had fallen out of the bag on the way. Find the minimum number of marbles that could have fallen out of the bag.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"35","CORRECT_ANSWER":"35","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">N marbles can be distributed equally among P children, where N &gt; P. What is the number of values that N can assume such that P &gt; 1 and 2 &lt; N + P &lt; 100?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"70","CORRECT_ANSWER":"70","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A trader sells cakes in economy packs of four cakes per pack, each pack being charged at the listed price of three cakes. For every set of five such packs bought by a customer, the trader gives him one extra cake as a free gift. If a customer buys 12 economy packs, what is the effective percentage of discount that he gets?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>35 <img Width='25' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABkAAAAgCAYAAADnnNMGAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAANcSURBVEhLrZXJT1NBHMcbEsBwkSNlkWAiGKMUTFj+ADzgEYsJeMFwaPAgRSIxgIbVA1tFoSjSRBoFA2oiSuFAWEQwoGwBUhekQAIGWUQQaMvy9b1fh6ePloiv\/SS\/ZOY3k\/lkZn7zngx\/YTabodVWQqVSUWirqmC1WtmodESS87GxcHd3h1IZj3ilEjKZDAkJiWxUOoIkPzeXFn38pI5lgJLiIspVVGpZRhqCpLGxAcnJydja2mIZ4OvEBElUqhSWkYbouPZz7245SZ49f8Ey0jhQ8ra7mwQxMeewvb3NstJwKOns6CBBVFQ0VlfXWFY6dhJdzUMSJCRewsbGBss6h0hy62Y2CYqKilnGNQgSQ3MzCeLiLsBkMmF8fByjo6MUs7OzbNYffq6sQKfToa6uDlaL+MGaJieh1+uFhyxIwsPCSOIokpIus1k21tbWoAgNhb9\/AORyOSIiI\/FrfZ2NApEREVAowoSCESTt7e1obW1FS0sLDAaDKMbGxtgsG3p9Lcm\/LyxiyjRJ7YaGRhp719tD\/Q8DA9Tnsbv4w1BaUkwL7ezuAlzw7eKSUhoLUyigjL9I7T0kSaof3KeFzWYLfiwvU\/vV62a86eqk9tT0DJtpQ5Jkfn4efn6+dBeh3N0Eh5ykXYUEn0AiV\/o8FosFOzs71JYk4fk2N4fMzExkZWVhidtNK3d3\/C4WFhZwR6OBr68vgoKO42VTE2RtbW1IT0+HWq3+ZwwNDTGFPXIfH+Tk5uHL508kq6nRIS8nB25ubpD19PSgurr6UGE0GtmSYrSVFbTwFleytwsKqM1j4X6CXl5e0o9rD\/7BeXsf5U7jOvWzszIFiZW7F5dIykpLaNGlpSXqd3XaKuxRbS0KC\/Lh6XnEOQn\/8s+eDUdpmYZlbBRyR8bfUWBgIAzc4xYkvdxL3f\/S+dfPfwVmZsR1vwd\/VLzIEZubm8JfVpCcOX2KtukoNJpyNksagoT\/n+99dfl439\/P1bocAQHHML3vBf8vB97JjYwM2kVfXz\/LSMehZHBwgAQpKVdYxjkcSqKjIuHh4YnFRVtZOoudZGRkmHaRqk5jGeexk6RfSyOJ0fiRZZxHJNnm6tqPq6jgkBCWcQ0iydSUiXZxNVXNMq5BJBkeGiRJff1TlnEFwG8Ikwh17sTTxwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='44' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAgCAYAAABpRpp6AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAUrSURBVFhHzVd5TNRHFF5uCcgpNHLUxh5psVrTQ+ifWCAG\/Edh16tRkbUiJdqCkKZNbdIWqlDAowj4h4o25WpBGqtYEbCCtmpqjZWz4UgQpQE5lvvw65u3s4gtVLu\/3cYvecl738zOfjPz5s38VPgf8EVyEmJiYjA0NCQZ42F2wWdO\/wALCwu4urpLRhnMKriuthZWVlZwdnaGi4srenp6ZYvxMJvg8fFxPLtwIULDVmJ79DZaZcsnW\/CWyEjY2tpCpxvAjth3oVKpnlzB+Xl5LLCysorjrdoojkdHxzhWApMLbqivh52dHVatDkdbWxvqKQ5fvYoFX7lyVfEqm1zw\/n37WNxsdvCrTNnTOJhccGtrK0pLS1FSUoLi4mK2t5YHstgTJ75Gc0uL7GkcpgTX1dUiOSkJcXFxOHDgIO7cvStb9JicnMTx3FzEx8cjKTmZ+tfJlkcjakskC54NZWfOIDAwEKGhoaiurpGsHvn5eYiIiMDI6CjHPMr3tCJiQFtbOyxdupT9+fO9cOtWLXcaHBykVVrOvJ+fH2xtbGBpaYWysrPc\/ijsio+Dr68v+vr6JfMATY2NNJYlNm+OhEajhpW1NVpolwREaZw71xGbqM0A1Z2ODsyhQ7J4ySvo6upm8vKlGhYVEPAmx4dzsllsZuYhjtvb2+Hj7Q1vbx8Mj4ww928YGxvDyCz9DuzX57zAGK2i8LOycjjOzjoEC5pMV1cXxwKqluZmhISEUM6dlJQeAf7L6McW7H\/80Yc8kMhPA9avXcNc970eyRiHtC9TpwTj\/n3291NK3iff3t4ee1NS9W0SMybWyPAwXaXOePW11zn+5efLtDVzeWta6NB8W1TEg6nVGkxMTHAfY1FS\/B2LvHHjJi7V1LD\/6\/XfqNpkUHmcg1HanemYUfCmjRv5h+fKz0sG+GT3buYM5u3jQznZJ1uNx8TEONZoNPQ4cuVFiYrS8iJY0xskPWMf9ykvP0eHsZr9fwjWRulvpazsbMkAuceOwoYOg0azBhUVFTh8OAdOTk4ICgrGwMCA7KUMV69ewbVr19j\/\/LNP4ebuzrm\/MiyMH09ONJmd773\/QPAQVYKQ4GAWm5eXL1n9SX3a1wdedMim48TxXO5bUFjEsXjrarVarFix4rFMTHwmdFI5FeOeOnUaVdRH+E1Nf6Di\/Hn2WbBO148lixfDw8OTZqqfpQG6\/n7aHku8scxfMnqIK1gMkJaewbHYRpHfj2uzpdP26Gh4ej7F\/geJifwfApM0vkgblfgjdUQ4bOhldZ2SXUCn07EZtlvcVNbWNmhoaORYYOtWLQ9WXl4uGeX4s7OTxzxy5CjHqSl7pwTf6+6CBfmq\/LxvmBTm4ODARdxg8+Z5UP0cxe83b9LsXLiPWq2m+uzP\/jvbonkwU2H92rW8y4bKU0+3rw3dB+vWrUNwUBBefMkPquqLF5GamsqWRFfzdEtLS8fwsL7gt1ENTkhIQDDleQSJLigoYN5UECny9oYNqKq6IBk9qior+coWC9V++\/bMZU0JxOFLTExAbGzsQyYmK6y1tU32NA4mF9zb24uF9Gnk5uY2ZV5eXlNp9\/dD\/V9hcsEz4dyPZ1lsXFw8v\/qUwOyCh+maFw+lRYte5veBUphdcMKueF7dmppLklEGswruoFMtamdQcIhklMOsglP27OHVvXDhJ8koh9kEi3x94fnnsGDBM4oP2nSYTbD49BGru2PHTsmYBmYTXFhYwIJPniyVjGlgNsE59J52dHSkD0plN9vDAP4CmgCO+0jNLYUAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='43' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACsAAAAgCAYAAACLmoEDAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAW+SURBVFhHzZdpTFVHFMcfIlSRHQUeAhJRK9hoP7i00qJNpUVRnhsasSXQslRbF1zaGAGpULoIamgiWrBWNsUKRBsFoSJQZVEkwVobqVqelK2gVnZQ+XfmvHksygdz3zXxl7y8mTPn3vnfmTNnZhR4AVyrqkJISEj\/78CBBNGiG7KLbWtrxeRJk+Ds7Ix9+\/djlY8P9PT0cPjwj8JDOrKL3R0ZCYVCgUslpcICvPnGHIwabYSuri5hkYbsYuNiY4XYEmEB5syeBcNXRr18YltaWrBgwbuYONEZUVFRUHl7w8TEBCczM4WHdGQX29vTg48C\/Gl07e3tYWBggHHjrFFVdU14SEd2sUGBH5PQzMwsqjc1NmLWzJkwZqNbU6Mmm1RkFdvZ2QkT4zGYPuN1YdFw6eJF+oDU1DRhkYasYntYCFiPG4vJU14VFg2\/nD6tEZuWLizS6Bd7kX19XFwcEhOT0NjUJKwD\/FNbi4SEBMSy1V5YWCiszxK5K4KEhYWFo5GFQFlpKcZaWcLCwhINDQ3Ca4A\/b9yAn58f1q5di4qKCmHVUFBwHsHBwejq7qa6oq+vDxER4dSBra0tjIyMYG5ugZycXHLg5OedY9NrjJEjDaBUKsnX3z8A\/Nmn6e3twfp168jH0NCQ\/qewkS5lop\/mwYMHULI+3efNw\/Lly+j9N6urRSvg6OCAhYu8+vtR\/HTkCL1w584wMvDUM4ntPkqlHZvWXjx+\/BhOExxhZzce9fX15LNt61Z6Jjv7FNWHQ62uQXFxMSorK9k7ngjrUE6fOkXvqW9opLq+\/gjEfP0NlbMyT1KbWn2X6hzFr\/n52LZtO7q7e4RpYEXX1TWgo6ODyt6qpaIVqL2rJlt4xC5hkcbPJzLoPc3NLVQ3MTHGThY+HFsba2z\/\/Asqa3lmgd25fRsTHB0x1+0tPHmiGRGV9xJYWY1FERspHrvLlqrYi03Z1JZRu1RKSi6R2PMFF\/D3nTtUzj2Xh4zjx6jc2toqPDX0i71\/7x7bFmeTE4+d69f\/EC1gC6UBjo4O1Kb97dkTK1p1IygwkK0Rc1haWkK1VDN7lhYW\/WHJQ6msrJzK\/WL5V5zIyEBycjKcnJwwbdprTGQTpSM3t7mwtrbBwYOH2MLLwZLFi2FqZoac3IFFqAs8C\/BsxDl0MIEWeUdHJ1av8oEZ+xBz1tfm0C3D59miokIavbi9+1AsykmDjnh9LDzsx9vBxXWasAAZ7EM9PT2f63f58mXx1FDa29pgyLbno8kpqLhyhfq99vt1\/FZcpJnR3Nwc7NixA48ePRKP8JRynxp3RX6JlKNHqXzhwtDcOn+eO8xZ7tTS3NzMVq76uX7t7e3iqaFEhIfRtsyJ+Sqa+uUZiQ0Py9VWUGwJDSVjWvoxcuJoE\/tZlmtv37pF5eCQT0Qr2MiUY8QIPbz3vqew6A4\/tI\/U18deNpscHg5asf+xfMwP8IqHDx\/Ca9FCavDw8IC7+9tU9lm1mn8Qof2gqVNdoFKpqGzv4Ijq6r80DjLw6fp1GGNs0p9C1TU1MGWj7MXWxzvz52P69BmamOWJPz4+HitXroSvry+ysrPpgcGcPXOG7Vr+WLFiBWJiYtA0zJYsFX4o37hxA\/Ly8oVFQ+XVq\/BdswYBAQGsv3+HX2C6Ul5eRjPA72Fz3dyQfmwgxHRBdrFXWRoaPXoUTE3NaOF6sw2Fh010dIzwkI7sYr0WauL\/5s2BA4nfhx+QjU+lLsgqlh++zc1MMeOpw\/c5lh652JPi9iAVWcXy3U5pY0NHwsGkpaaQ2JSX6abA2bjhMxIWH\/891evr6uDq4kK29PTjZJOK7GJ5StPman675YcSVxdXMbKpwksasovVkp2VRVegAnb8KxVHwZcqZjlJiT8glO14gwkOCiSxtewsrAuyi42O2k3Cvv1uD10YkxITqR4YFCw8pPNCwmDzpk0wZhdMfrnkZ9NQdhbVHeB\/rQnZ60dkuuAAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>28%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">A circular pizza is cut into four identical pieces (or quadrants) with two diametrical cuts made perpendicular to each other. Each piece can be topped with any one of five available toppings but no two adjacent pieces have the same topping. In how many ways can the four pieces be topped?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"70","CORRECT_ANSWER":"70","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">Consider a natural number <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">m<\/i><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> <\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">&times; (<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">m<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> &gt; 2) and <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> = 2<\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">m<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\"> + 1. Let X be the sum of the two-digit numbers as shown below (each two-digit number written in the number system to the base <\/span><i style=\"font-family: Arial;\">n<\/i><span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">):<\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">X = (12)<sub>n<\/sub> + (34)<sub>n<\/sub> + &hellip;&hellip; ([<i>2<\/i><i>m<\/i> &ndash; 1] [<i>2<\/i><i>m<\/i>])<sub>n<\/sub> <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">Express X + <i>m<\/i> + 2 in base <i>m<\/i>. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"2222","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2222","UNIT":"<p>\r\n\t<em>m<\/em><\/p>","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">On a certain sum, the difference between the compound interest and the simple interest for the second year is Rs.3,600 and the same for the third year is Rs.7,740. What is the sum? Assume that in case of compound interest, compounding is done annually.<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1,60,000\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1,20,000\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Rs.1,80,000\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p>\r\n\t<span style=\"font-family: Arial;\">In a game show, a contestant is given three boxes and asked to choose one of them. Only one of the three boxes contains a prize. After the contestant chooses one of the boxes, the host opens that box. If that box contains the prize, the contestant wins it. Else, the host allows the contestant a last chance to choose one of the two remaining boxes. What is the probability that the contestant wins the prize?<\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHQSURBVDhP1ZTLLwNRFManG1qCaEpJ2g0WSFg0CAvWTdUCO+JNaue5rscf4BFrbdIEe6+wpQuDsClJd10o7UZp03Z00c\/MmWvSMtOdhC+5mTnn++Wec2\/uvRw0dHR0CJfLhVQqxTKAKnx9zcNcXY3y8gqWkZUHP4fDmBVn4zgOer0elZVGxGJvzP0Gb21uwGAwwOP1YmZ6CjqdThuORCKiGaP\/6alJqqAJ52pyYvzfwSPDQwS\/vsoLlqQJLy8twmq14v09zjIF4EwmA0EQWCRLE1bTL8LZbBaJRALxeLzgkBjO5\/PB4XDAbrcXHBLDJZNJ1ZnUxl\/ZDfYlBQIBjI2Nwmazwel04uzsnDmyFPj+7k68oGV0Sefm5tHV2UkHaXfXw4gceHCgn8xQKMQyQEN9Hcw1tRA+PihW4GAwCJ7nWSSruakRZWKldDpN8Y8FSvvu9\/vFI7qEktJS7O0fMEcF5vkrOsdSSyZTFa5yqv2ABSFNT1Y4\/ISO9jYUFRfj4eGRvDz4q7cv+S8vqML29g7FCtzn7EVLSyuLZJ2eHMvb5\/FSrMCLCwtkrK6tIxqN4vbmBjVmM713Ly8RYvLaWHG7YTQaYbFYxMWZ0N3do\/QLAJ+NE7o+YYMqmQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAGaSURBVDhP1dS9S0JRGAbwWygOQnIb6h+xtcI0zLbCraJUULOpbK72tA8\/slqlGrRvqAYbBcnN1USHDETMELXEfOq+Hi4aemm0F1445zk\/ONxzD4dDl7q9uYbVakWlUmEJ0BHH408YHhrCwICKJc1qw6+vWTgcy+A4DgqFAjw\/iLe3Ilv9hXd33JDL5Tg6OobFbEZfX393nM2+IJ\/P09hiNtEOXXFrmZYW\/x1emJ\/7O175OW+e51EsvrNEApfLZRQKBTQaDZZI4E7VKzgYDMJgMECv10u2YLhcLod0Oo1MJiPZgunF0\/ioVuHz+WA0Gqn9\/gN81mpstQWXSiWMqNV0eTQaDbUwntDq6NcLJeKtzQ1aPDk9Ywngdm1T5vF6aS7i83AYdrsd9XqdJcBzMknYZrPTXPIDd9wuwheXVzTvih8jEYJThml8fTWvaUf8cH9HcHRsXPr58uzvETRbLKi1HJtQbdi5tkowEDhkSXuJOBwKEZyZmUUikUAsFkM0GqVOpVJkRDyp00KpVEKlUtF7J5PJxHY6138E8A3LkbpcS3rhzQAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAfCAYAAAAx6zerAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAI6SURBVDhPzZTPa5JxHMcfL+L00GYsnOuigczSBQsWs4PGOq579QdMFosc\/hgMl7DILi7WYRtsopayGtUhdYd1yILVjguaczkQ3MnZxdNaiL77Pp\/nyxefgnXdGz7wvN\/v1\/OT5\/uV0KHlpSV4vV7VhELTvAVUsH1gAH19Zng8HjHj417edsCVSgWSJCE2\/4wn\/0rAHzY3CU6lXmB9\/TWy2SwajQZvFQn48dwcwXq9HiaTCRqNBkbjeXwsFDjRAU+HgujtvYD37IrtdhvVahUOxxXodDrU6z+JUb1gs9nkR4pera2JR5Ml4HK5jPLBAXeKNvJ5ghcXl8kL+JLVgp4eI3eKHkxOElwq7ZMXcHx1lYrR0VtIZzLw+R6Sn5i4z4m\/njmTTuPa0BDMZjNsNhtisXn2srxkUsH\/01mBi8Ui++gpJBKJUyeZTELK5XIIBALw+\/2njsyc1a9R2ttDNPoEkUgEW1tfeKpIBT9fWKD\/wWq1wmKx0PHsowhvO+Di7i6Vd+7e4wlwe2yMsu+skyXg8MwMFScnv3kCWoPxeBxHR3XyAr7pdqO\/\/yIymTRcLhdbUg6Ew7O8VSTgQacTBoMB57q7EQgGMTXlozuNsBOPj38RI+Crg04qc\/kNnsj\/90vK3rx9R17AN1wj6OrSo9Vq8QQ4PKwSHI0+JS\/gELu1XJT2lfUm69vODmUrK3HyAv7BIA0r3G4P7RnyXB8ehlarRa1WI0bAsj5\/KrBVbqUdSR67\/TK+bm\/zFvgDxBdNxHdoWAcAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='11' Height= '32' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAsAAAAgCAYAAADEx4LTAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAItSURBVDhPzZQ\/TBNxFMevSZtqWbCpEmyFnbqUQR26NVHTWCD+ATtwOmAaHAjgIEvbQSWOFKUJRnAq0LKgradbgwNKQoskSBkwbUoCSZs06dKmTfXr9d3P805O4sg3ecm99\/3c79773S8\/DgpVq1XMzLyEz+ejCIfDqNVqzAVU8PVrV2E0noLX6xXjLnQ6HfoHBpirgIMBPziOQ2x5mVWAUGiKalOhacplOBGPY3z8ERqNH6wCfN\/bI3h4+CHlqjb+1vPJSYIT7wXK\/wm\/XVkh8E6\/Rs9KLS0uENjT2ye21WBVDfj3oI8nJljlj1Tw\/Xs8DAYD3sUTrKKWDL+anaUVb3g8EAQBsVgM0WiUYmMjRYwMX7l8SfwhRuj1enpJGUNDD4iR4f39PPJ57SiVSsQcGfA4nRQ4EonAI26X2+0+NpoMVygUkMvl\/itO4m7kslmMjY3C5XKB53msrX1mjiQZzuzsoK3tHJ26wUEe9q4uOhcLi0uMUMC3b90kM7O7yyo\/0dnZAduFDvk6kOGtra9IJpMsk3TRbsdpUwsq4n3S1JEBmxdNKpVCMBiAyWTC3Pwb5mjA6+tfYLVaqSWL5SzSm5vM0YArlQrK5TKy4s50Oxzi6i3IZKQ5VHC9XmdPkj6trtIXQtMvKJfhvt4eOBzdLJP08YNA8Ou5ecpleHRkhIwnT5+hWCwinU7jfHs7WlvP4ODgkBhVGwG\/H2azGTabTRzOAqfTie3tb8wFfgEivpSxyg5cMgAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"}}